Ian Hundere

Atlanta, GA | (512) 410-0083 ian.hunde.re | github.com/ianhundere | linkedin.com/in/ianhundere | ian@hunde.re "perpetually taking an open book test while having fun"

Summary

I'm an enthusiastic problem solver with years of experience working with developers, IaaS (AWS), and multiple data sources to produce highly integrated solutions. Well experienced with version control, tool selection, and pipeline building. While cloud infrastructure is my professional specialty, personally I have built several full-stack and front-end applications using Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB, and Tone.js as well as an assortment of Bash/Python scripts. I also self-host a number of applications (Ninjam, Nextcloud, UniFi, etc) via a 5 node (1 x86 and 4 Raspberry PIs) K3s cluster.

Skills

AWS, Kubernetes, Terraform, Linux, Bash, Python, Docker, Ansible, Git, Packer, Vagrant, Datadog, New Relic, Zabbix, Sumo Logic, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, Consul, Vault, Flux, Argo CD, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI, CircleCI, PostgreSQL

Experience

DevOps Engineer II | Oddball | Atlanta, GA

April 2022 - Present

- Lead of the DevOps Community of Practice; facilitate discussions and presentations surrounding best practices and lessons learned as well as mentor junior engineers to improve technical growth and effectiveness
- Develop and implement custom GitHub Actions; for instance, using Slack's Block Kit and Bash to detect Terraform drift providing detailed formatted information of potential creates, updates, and destroys of infrastructure resources (e.g. AWS GovCloud, Datadog, etc) via Slack
- Apply log processing rules (e.g. regex) to drop unwanted/noisy logs at both the deployment level using podAnnotations and Datadog agent level using Helm (microservice environments) or Datadog configuration file (monolith environments)
- Create custom IAM permissions boundary to prevent privilege escalation and limit scope of IAM users and roles
- Resolve long running API routes (third-party services) by rerouting via Nginx redirects to secondary ASG and LB resources built using Terraform data sources applied via CI/CD pipelines; short-term fix
- Convert a variety of Jenkins jobs to GitHub Composite Actions
- Research and prepare the move of a Ruby based Sign-in Service controller from a monolith infrastructure (e.g. a
 containerized monolith hosted on dedicated EC2 instances deployed via Ansible and Jenkins) to a microservice
 infrastructure (e.g. deployed to EKS via Argo CD and GitHub Actions) to improve resiliency and availability

Cloud Infrastructure Engineer II | Revel Systems | Atlanta, GA

November 2020 – April 2022

- Lead effort to improve developer velocity by bundling monitoring (e.g. EKS, ECS, EC2, RDS etc.) with deployments through custom Terraform modules using the Datadog provider
- Rebuild GitLab Runner EKS cluster by improving its IaC, availability and disaster recovery through automation
- Develop a modular CLI Bash script used by the entire Infrastructure team to do a variety of tasks such as
 accessing RDS per PCI standards with optional flags to list schemas, users, long running queries as well as pass
 valid SQL
- Build Ansible playbooks; for instance, to enable RDS IAM authentication and seed RDS instances with users/roles
- Increase developer velocity by assisting development teams with Terraform, GitLab CI/CD pipelines, AWS, *nix, containerization, etc. including creating tools (e.g. Terraform modules, CI/CD templates, scripts) for them to use
- Mentor junior engineers through regular check-ins, postmortems, and purposeful questions

DevOps Engineer | Artis Technologies, LLC | Atlanta, GA

February 2020 - November 2020

- Configure and maintain EKS clusters for multiple deployments
- Automate tasks with Bash scripts, Kubernetes Jobs, Kubernetes CronJobs, and AWS Lambda functions
- Install, configure, and maintain Sumo Logic, Datadog, CloudWatch, New Relic, and Falco to monitor site reliability, durability, integrity and confidentiality
- Implement CI/CD pipelines using CircleCI
- Performance tune pipelines to decrease deployment times by 60%

Software Engineer, DevOps & Training Platforms | Itential, LLC | Atlanta, GA January 20

January 2019 - February 2020

- Configure and automate Itential's learning environment used by internal employees, external customers, and potential customers using Ansible and Docker
- Improve the launch time of lab containers by 30%
- Create RESTful APIs using Express and Puppeteer to automate CRUD operations (e.g. student enrollment/unenrollment; brittle, not a good idea)
- Deploy and configure openLDAP, Netbox, Zabbix and Grafana

Academic Technology Coach | Northside Independent School District | San Antonio, TX July 2016 – June 2018

- Create and teach a variety of professional development to improve teachers' instruction efficacy at 7 campuses
- Identify technology integration competencies among instructional staff in collaboration with administrators to deliver effective coaching to accelerate the professional growth of adult learners
- Make decisions related to instructional technology acquisition and deployment to encourage student engagement and academic rigor

Teacher, 4th and 5th grade | Pflugerville Independent School District | Austin, TX August 2013 – June 2016

- Utilize diverse teaching strategies to effectively address each student's learning style and ability
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

Product Specialist Support | Apple Inc. | Austin, TX

September 2007 – August 2012

- Assist a number of companies (e.g. OfficeMax, Best Buy, etc.) with their support of Apple products
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

Education

DigitalCrafts | Full-Stack Web Development | Atlanta, GA
Texas State University | Master in Education | San Marcos, TX
University of Victoria | B.A. in History | Victoria, B.C., Canada

September 2018 – January 2019 August 2010 – December 2012 September 2002 – August 2007